In this series of units, I've given you a small part of the research findings in negotiating.
If you want to know more about me, you can see my details after this final unit.
Let's look at implementation.
It's a big subject, and I'll cover two points only.
First of all, particularly if it's a complex implementation involving new technology, or involving many departments and people; follow up is crucial.
The rule about follow up is you do not follow things up when problems arrive, you follow up while the ink' is still wet on the contract.
The quicker you can get into support and follow up, the less likely you are to confront problems and difficulties.
But they will arise, and sometimes people say, it's your fault this went wrong.
The other side will say, no it isn't because your position that you took up on this was wrong in the first place.
I'll warn you, this will happen; in major negotiations it happens; however much you plan to avoid it in the negotiation itself.
The key issue is to avoid blame.
The quicker you can get into asking for solutions, and what can be done about it, the more likely you are to minimize the disruption and the cost of an implementation failure.
This has been some ideas on negotiating, and I hope that they're ones that you can use in the future.
Good hunting.